<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Object Detection on Cylopsis- an elucidation of ML</title>
    <link>http://cylopsis.com/tags/object-detection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Object Detection on Cylopsis- an elucidation of ML</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Jagpreet Singh Chawla</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 12:52:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cylopsis.com/tags/object-detection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Realtime Face Attribute Detection</title>
      <link>http://cylopsis.com/post/computer-vision/face-attribute-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 12:52:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cylopsis.com/post/computer-vision/face-attribute-detection/</guid>
      <description>In my article about object detection approaches, I mentioned a few ways to handle object detection and introduced YOLO NN model which uses a single Neural Network to simultaneously localize as well as classify the objects. It uses a regression approach to detect the object by dividing the image into a grid. To me, it seems really simple but innovative approach and I wanted to try it out myself. So I decided to rewrite my live gender classifier to use only one NN to detect as well as classify faces in one single go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Detection Approaches</title>
      <link>http://cylopsis.com/post/computer-vision/object-detection-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 12:19:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cylopsis.com/post/computer-vision/object-detection-approaches/</guid>
      <description>In my previous article, I created a live face detection with gender recognition using 2 different models. We used an OpenCV provided cascade classifier to detect faces, and used our trained Neural Network to classify detected faces. But cascade classifier is very weak and detects faces only in front view. We can combine more models for side views, but still, it will not be as good as a NN based approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>